<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FIM 2010 R2 on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/fim-2010-r2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FIM 2010 R2 on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 13:39:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/fim-2010-r2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christmastime FIM/MIM Open Source WF Reviews</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2016/12/christmastime-fimmim-open-source-wf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 13:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2016/12/christmastime-fimmim-open-source-wf.html</guid>
      <description>Over the years since FIM was first beta&amp;rsquo;d as ILM2 we have seen some cool workflows be released to open source. This is my review of the workflows I can find that are open source. First let me salute everyone who has contributed to the FIM and MIM community with these big undertakings. That said I am trying to give guidance to my readers as to what is the most useful in various situations and so I will make specific recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Custom Expressions inside Custom Expressions?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/11/fim-custom-expressions-inside-custom.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 10:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/11/fim-custom-expressions-inside-custom.html</guid>
      <description>Recently, I needed to take Longitude and Latitude data that was given to me in the following format and break it into its individual components and then flow it out to AD.
Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose the data looks like this:
&amp;ldquo;Point -10.1223 45.945&amp;rdquo;
I could just use the Left and Right functions to get out the Longitude and Latitude.
The problem was it could also look like this depending on the level of precision:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIM 2016 is now available</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/08/mim-2016-is-now-available.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 08:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/08/mim-2016-is-now-available.html</guid>
      <description>MIM 2016 is now available
MIM &amp;ndash; Microsoft Identity Manager 2016 builds on and replaces Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Forefront Identity Manager 2010 R2.
On Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s site they include an introductory (2 min) video about Hybrid Identity but don&amp;rsquo;t mistake that for the MIM UI.
So has anything been removed?
No. While the list of deprecated features are still deprecated none of them have been removed from this new version.
So what&amp;rsquo;s new?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Hotfix for PCNS to support 2012 R2 DC&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/04/fim-hotfix-for-pcns-to-support-2012-r2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 13:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/04/fim-hotfix-for-pcns-to-support-2012-r2.html</guid>
      <description>With the latest hotfix MSFT now supports running PCNS on Windows Server 2012 R2. FIM still should not be installed on Windows Server 2012 R2 (2012 yes, 2008 R2 yes, 2008 yes). Only PCNS can be installed on Windows Server 2012 R2. The hotfix article has a slight error indicating that it is ok to install FIM Sync Service on 2012 R2 if you have installed the hotfix PCNS on 2012 R2 &amp;ndash; not true (the article should get corrected soon).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Maintenance for FIM and anything other databases</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/10/sql-maintenance-for-fim-and-anything.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 17:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/10/sql-maintenance-for-fim-and-anything.html</guid>
      <description>An easy way to take care for your FIM databases is to &amp;ldquo;use Ola Hallengren&amp;rsquo;s script (http://ola.hallengren.com/scripts/MaintenanceSolution.sql). Download the script, adjust the backup paths and run the script on each instance of SQL Server. It will automatically create several jobs some for maintaining the system databases and some for maintain the user databases. You will need to create schedules for each of the jobs.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; FIM Best Practices Volume 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Farm, or not to Farm, that is the question --</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/05/to-farm-or-not-to-farm-that-is-question.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 12:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/05/to-farm-or-not-to-farm-that-is-question.html</guid>
      <description>In some environments, like government, having that&amp;hellip; REALHIPHOPINYOURLIFE - May 5, 2014
In some environments, like government, having that local SQL means a whole different security profile&amp;hellip;a lot of security groups aren&amp;rsquo;t going to make a distinction between that local SQL and Full Blown SQL when they scan the system since they use some of the same binaries.
Good comment. So in those environments that could be an extra reason to farm to avoid local SQL and the extra security</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Farm, or not to Farm, that is the question --</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/05/to-farm-or-not-to-farm-that-is-question.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 12:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/05/to-farm-or-not-to-farm-that-is-question.html</guid>
      <description>Whether &amp;rsquo;tis nobler in the mind to suffer the slings and arrows of outrageous fortune Or to take Farms against a sea of patches and by opposing end them? To, die, to sleep &amp;ndash; Today I will be &amp;ldquo;moderating&amp;rdquo; the debate about using SharePoint Farms vs. Stand-Alone as the foundation for the FIM Portal. In this corner we have Paul Williams of Microsoft sharing knowledge from his hard fought victories with FIM and painful experiences with Farms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New name for FIM?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/new-name-for-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 08:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/new-name-for-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Actually it&amp;rsquo;s MIM (Microsoft Identity Manager)&amp;hellip; Oliver Hanappi - Apr 3, 2014
Actually it&amp;rsquo;s MIM (Microsoft Identity Manager). See http://blogs.technet.com/b/server-cloud/archive/2014/04/23/forefront-identity-manager-vnext-roadmap-now-microsoft-identity-manager.aspx
Like any good futurist I guessed so many things that one of them was bound to be right http://blog.ilmbestpractices.com/2013/07/the-mvp-7-year-itch.html?m=1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New name for FIM?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/new-name-for-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 08:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/new-name-for-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Did you know that if you subscribe to Azure AD Premium you also get licenses for FIM? Well if that isn&amp;rsquo;t a hand tipper I don&amp;rsquo;t know what is. I think we can safely assume the next version of FIM will have Azure in the name. Safe or not I am going speculate that it will.
Azure Identity Manager (AIM) &amp;ndash; I would be ok with this
Azure Role Based Access Manager (ARBAM) &amp;ndash; Explosive sounding name</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hints of FIM&#39;s Future: Azure Active Directory (AAD) Sync</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/hints-of-fims-future-azure-active.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 08:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2014/04/hints-of-fims-future-azure-active.html</guid>
      <description>For years I have been trying to predict the future of Identity Management, but every time I look in my crystal ball it is just too cloudy to see anything. In fact anytime I look in my crystal ball on just about any technology topic the only thing it shows me are clouds! I was beginning to think it was broken.
But then, yesterday, I watched Andreas Kjellman present at the FIM user group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DirSync w/ domain if NetBios and FQDN don&#39;t match</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/dirsync-w-domain-if-netbios-and-fqdn.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 16:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/dirsync-w-domain-if-netbios-and-fqdn.html</guid>
      <description>If one of your AD domains has a NetBios domain name that doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the leftmost part of your FQDN you need to have the Replicating Directory Changes permission given to your AD MA account. This is documented in a few places including my book. However, DirSync misses this step. Normally, Dirsync does a very good job of installing and configuring everything which you need without needing you to be an expert in FIM, but this is one thing it misses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declarative or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</guid>
      <description>I see two challenges: 1. There is not feature pari&amp;hellip; Craig Martin - Oct 3, 2013
I see two challenges:
1. There is not feature parity between the two types of sync rules
2. The imperative support (VBA) in the new sync rules is limited and difficult to debug
My wish is that we had better extensibility in the new sync rules (scrap VBA, or figure out how to improve the extensibility and debugging).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declarative or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</guid>
      <description>Michael Pearn from down under wrote about his experience trying to use just Declarative Sync Rules
His experience &amp;ndash; especially the religious debates are similar to my own. It made me recall my presentation at TEC 2012 the FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative
The vast majority of old hands at the presentation declared for Classic both before and after the presentation. During the presentation I attempted to view anything you could do without code as declarative whether it came from a sync rule or not, especially if it was a new feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get from the Sync-Rule-ID to the Sync Rule Resource ID</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/05/how-to-get-from-sync-rule-id-to-sync.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 12:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/05/how-to-get-from-sync-rule-id-to-sync.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks, David. You had the knowledge, answered my &amp;hellip; Unknown - May 3, 2013
Thanks, David. You had the knowledge, answered my forum question and blogged about it as well. Nice work.
PeteA</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get from the Sync-Rule-ID to the Sync Rule Resource ID</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/05/how-to-get-from-sync-rule-id-to-sync.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 12:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/05/how-to-get-from-sync-rule-id-to-sync.html</guid>
      <description>If you are looking at the XML export of the FIM synchronization config and you are trying to track down which sync rule is supplying a particular flow you just need to know which numbers lead you where.
For example:
The key to finding the Sync rule is of course the Sync rule ID. However, this is not the resource ID that I can search for in the FIM Portal. Rather this is the metaverse ID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Functions Updated, Bitwise Functions</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/04/fim-functions-updated-bitwise-functions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 10:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/04/fim-functions-updated-bitwise-functions.html</guid>
      <description>In addition to the official reference for functions I thought I would update my examples from back in the ILM 2 Beta days
Function Name
BitAnd
Parameters
mask Type: Integer
flag Type: Integer
Description
BitAnd is a bitwise operation anding mask and flag. So if Flag is the UserAccountControl Attribute in AD and mask is **-3
**(the 64-bit two&amp;rsquo;s complement of 2) Then the result is that the disable bit (bit 2) is turned off leaving all of the other bits unchanged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight Cloud SSO Solution and FIM Jumpstart offerings</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/insight-cloud-sso-solution-and-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/insight-cloud-sso-solution-and-fim.html</guid>
      <description>I wrote an article for the Insight Newsletter about two of our new offerings.
Solving identity and access management for mid-sized business
By David Lundell, Sr. Manager, Identity and Security Practice
User productivity, IT budgets, and security and compliance all suffer from ineffective identity and access management. Insight has two new packages aimed at helping mid-sized businesses confront these challenges in the age of the cloud. Read more.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 5</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/secrets-of-metaverse-part-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/secrets-of-metaverse-part-5.html</guid>
      <description>Parts 1-5:
What is the Metaverse? How is the Metaverse data stored? Is there a limit to how many Metaverse attributes I can have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? How do I safely query the metaverse? Added (Aug 5 2015): How Many Metaverse Attributes can I have? First of all the FIM Product group does not support direct modification of the data in any of the FIM databases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 4</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/secrets-of-metaverse-part-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/03/secrets-of-metaverse-part-4.html</guid>
      <description>Parts 1-5:
What is the Metaverse? How is the Metaverse data stored? Is there a limit to how many Metaverse attributes I can have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? How do I safely query the metaverse? Added (Aug 5 2015): How Many Metaverse Attributes can I have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? Well I won&amp;rsquo;t cover everything they have done but two really significant things:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 3</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 05:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>Parts 1-5:
What is the Metaverse? How is the Metaverse data stored? Is there a limit to how many Metaverse attributes I can have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? How do I safely query the metaverse? Added (Aug 5 2015): How Many Metaverse Attributes can I have? Many times people wonder how many attributes they can create in the Metaverse Designer tool.
The answer is confusing because &amp;hellip; it depends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 06:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>Parts 1-5:
What is the Metaverse? How is the Metaverse data stored? Is there a limit to how many Metaverse attributes I can have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? How do I safely query the metaverse? Added (Aug 5 2015): How Many Metaverse Attributes can I have? Where and how is the Metaverse data stored?
Before I get into that I must caution you that modifying data directly will put you in a position that is unsupported by Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 21:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>Great explanation. This really came in handy for t&amp;hellip; Unknown - Jul 2, 2013
Great explanation. This really came in handy for troubleshooting.
I am so glad it was of use
I am using MV extension to create users in AD from FIM.
Need to flow password to AD which is any Random number say &amp;ldquo;$random123&amp;rdquo;
This attribute flows to AD but can be viewed in account preview etc or the attribute value can be seen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the Metaverse Part 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 21:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/secrets-of-metaverse-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>Many FIMsters wonder about the Metaverse and how works, how the data is stored. In this series I will reveal the secrets of the Metaverse. Parts 1-5 (links live but post yet to come)
What is the Metaverse? How is the Metaverse data stored? Is there a limit to how many Metaverse attributes I can have? Has access to the metaverse gotten faster with recent releases? How do I safely query the metaverse?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated Vote: Top 5 Deprecated Features of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/updated-vote-top-5-deprecated-features.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 10:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/updated-vote-top-5-deprecated-features.html</guid>
      <description>Here is an update on the impact of the newly deprecated features: The big change is that XMA has caught up to Multi-Mastery and is tied for first.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive FIM and AD LDS project at DPDHL</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/massive-fim-and-ad-lds-project-at-dpdhl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 10:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/02/massive-fim-and-ad-lds-project-at-dpdhl.html</guid>
      <description>Watch the presentation that James Booth (who worked with us on the project) and Joe Gasowski (DPDHL) gave at the Redmond Identity Summit 2013 about our project at DHL to replace the DPDHL Sun One Directory and deploy FIM to replace both CriticalPath and a home-grown admin portal.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voted: Top 5 Deprecated Features of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/voted-top-5-deprecated-features-of-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 11:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/voted-top-5-deprecated-features-of-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Looks like ECMA1 deprecation has caught up to the &amp;hellip; Ross - Feb 4, 2013
Looks like ECMA1 deprecation has caught up to the equal precedence issue since you posted this.
I think I&amp;rsquo;ll start offering some ECMA1-&amp;gt;ECMA2 upgrade services. I suppose not everybody has an xMA developer in their back pocket!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voted: Top 5 Deprecated Features of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/voted-top-5-deprecated-features-of-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 11:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/voted-top-5-deprecated-features-of-fim.html</guid>
      <description>I conducted a linkedIn poll to find out what others thought of the features that are deprecated starting in FIM 2010 R2 SP1. For the poll I only listed the ones I put in my top 5 list. With 15 votes and 1 abstention I thought it would be worthwhile to publish the results:
Here we can see the winner:
Multi-mastery/equal precedence (I had this 2nd)
ECMA1 (XMA) (I had this third)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rest of the FIM 2010 R2 SP1 Deprecations</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/the-rest-of-fim-2010-r2-sp1-deprecations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 11:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/the-rest-of-fim-2010-r2-sp1-deprecations.html</guid>
      <description>Remember that these features are still here but will be removed in a future version (probably the next major release or the one after)
Feature
Impact
Unselect “allow nulls” for exported values
You need to be more careful to ensure that you aren&amp;rsquo;t deleting values
Web Service configuration interface
You will no longer be able to send a request to the web service to update the mv-data or ma-data objects in order to configure the sync engine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Deprecated features as of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/top-5-deprecated-features-as-of-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 11:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/top-5-deprecated-features-as-of-fim.html</guid>
      <description>I have heard that investments in FIM CM are contin&amp;hellip; David Lundell - Jan 2, 2013
I have heard that investments in FIM CM are continuing. So don&amp;rsquo;t worry about FIM CM disappearing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Deprecated features as of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/top-5-deprecated-features-as-of-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 11:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/top-5-deprecated-features-as-of-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Microsoft published a list of features that have been deprecated in FIM and will be removed from the product at some point in the future. In other words these don&amp;rsquo;t require immediate action but when the next major release of * Identity Manager (* because we don&amp;rsquo;t know what the new name will be &amp;ndash; see my tweet from last week at the Redmond Identity Summit) emerges those features will likely be gone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 11 new features of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/fim-2010-r2-sp1-documentation-and-bits.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 20:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/fim-2010-r2-sp1-documentation-and-bits.html</guid>
      <description>Hello, Is Fim r2 sp1 support sql server 2012 sp1 Unknown - Mar 2, 2015
Hello,
Is Fim r2 sp1 support sql server 2012 sp1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 11 new features of FIM 2010 R2 SP1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/fim-2010-r2-sp1-documentation-and-bits.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 20:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/01/fim-2010-r2-sp1-documentation-and-bits.html</guid>
      <description>My comments on What&amp;rsquo;s new and the release notes for FIM 2010 R2 SP1:
Rank
Feature
Impact
1
Deferred evaluation of criteria based groups
This setting can be enabled one group at a time. You can also change the default so that as new criteria based groups are created they will be set for Deferred. The default is to calculate group membership twice a day at 2:30 AM and 2:30 PM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons to be thankful for Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/11/5-reasons-to-be-thankful-for-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 15:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/11/5-reasons-to-be-thankful-for-identity.html</guid>
      <description>On the eve of Thanksgiving I offer 5 reasons to be thankful for Identity Management (user provisioning, deprovisioning, group and role management, etc.):
What other compliance project can actually have a positive ROI? You get improved compliance (and the ability to show it) You also get better security as accounts are disabled quickly Then you save money through the automation Identity Management can help support your corporate goals You can empower users to serve themselves with password resets, group/role requests It can help keep your organization out of the shame columns in the trade rags We have all read about the disgruntled former employee accessing data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Best Practices Volume 1 has been updated for R2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 09:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</guid>
      <description>We have purchased to original copy, are we entitle&amp;hellip; FMustafa - Sep 2, 2012
We have purchased to original copy, are we entitled to get a free upgrade to R2 version??
This comment has been removed by the author.
Any tentative date for print edition
The print edition is already available.
Just downloaded the EBook version from Lulu. Would love to see this available in a Kindle (or other e-reader) edition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Best Practices Volume 1 has been updated for R2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 09:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</guid>
      <description>Just this morning I have published the updated for R2 edition of FIM Best Practices Volume 1. Now called FIM R2 Best Practices Volume 1: Introduction, Architecture And Installation Of Forefront Identity Manager 2010 R2. The EBook edition is in color!
Print Edition of FIM R2 Best Practices Volume 1 is still B/W
Go to the lulu.com home page to get a coupon code for 20% off (offer expires 11:59 PM Sept 7 2012).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New version PCNS, new FIM hotfix</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/new-version-pcns-new-fim-hotfix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 09:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/new-version-pcns-new-fim-hotfix.html</guid>
      <description>SO, where (or when !?) can we download that hotfix ? redarc coder - Nov 2, 2014
SO, where (or when !?) can we download that hotfix ?
So, where (or when !?) can we download that hotfix !?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New version PCNS, new FIM hotfix</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/new-version-pcns-new-fim-hotfix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 09:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/new-version-pcns-new-fim-hotfix.html</guid>
      <description>On Aug 24th Microsoft released a new version of PCNS. Version number 4.1.2515.0.
No release notes are provided with the download. However, this version number matches the version number of the latest FIM R2 hotfix rollup http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2734159 and it does tell us what is fixed:
Assume that you run Password Change Notification Service (PCNS) setup together with the SCHEMAUPDATE=TRUE option and the schema is updated successfully. In this situation, an error message is displayed at the end of the setup process incorrectly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to import the Domain attribute into the FIM Portal Part 2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/how-to-import-domain-attribute-into-fim_16.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 13:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/how-to-import-domain-attribute-into-fim_16.html</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 of How to import the Domain attribute into the FIM Portal I provided you the simple technique for the single domain forest, and the technique that works although is a bit unwieldy – that of looking at the first 41 characters of the object’s SID and using a lookup table through nested IIF statements and this doesn’t .
What if there was a simpler way?
What about using the Domain Component option in the attribute flow?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to import the Domain attribute into the FIM Portal Part 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/how-to-import-domain-attribute-into-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 12:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/08/how-to-import-domain-attribute-into-fim.html</guid>
      <description>If you have a single domain forest then you should use a constant flow in your sync rule or advanced attribute flow. If you have a multi-domain forest, then using a constant in the advanced attribute flow won’t work.
You could create multiple inbound sync rules one for each domain with scoping filters and then use a constant. However, this seems like a waste.
You could also follow the guidance provided in article originated by my friend Markus Vilcinskas and maintained by the community http://social.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award for Me, Award for Insight</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 06:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on your renewal David! Henrik Nilsson - Jul 1, 2012
Congratulations on your renewal David!
Congratulations!!
Way to go man!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award for Me, Award for Insight</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 06:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</guid>
      <description>What a good week – Insight was awarded Microsoft Desktop Partner of the Year, and I just received news of my MVP award in the Forefront Identity Management area has been renewed.
The Desktop Partner of the Year is a great accomplishment by our Systems Management and Virtualization practice. This one will be added to all of the awards we won as Ensynch:
As for the MVP, I am always honored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 released today to MSDN</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/06/fim-2010-r2-released-today-to-msdn.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 19:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/06/fim-2010-r2-released-today-to-msdn.html</guid>
      <description>Look what just turned up on the MSDN list of downloads:
Along with FIM 2010 R2 it looks like the BHOLD Suite is available too! Although you can see that it appears to be a separate download.
I don’t know when the retail version will be available.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 Summary</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks David for a great overview of what was disc&amp;hellip; Henrik Nilsson - May 4, 2012
Thanks David for a great overview of what was discussed at TEC this year. I wish I could have attended but way too much work right now but I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to attend TEC Europe this year (if there&amp;rsquo;s gonna be any) and US next year.
Great to meet you David - thanks for the compliment ;) &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m one of those who&amp;rsquo;s been using your SQL scripts for years, and it was great to rub shoulders with so many bright people in this relatively small niche of ours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 Summary</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</guid>
      <description>Wow TEC 2012 is already over and I am already back home. What a week!
The venue was great. San Diego is always a great place to be, cool yet not too cold. Right on the bay. Great hotel. The Marriot Marquis and Marinas has an awesome pool – went for a great swim on Monday night. Tuesday morning I really enjoyed a jog on the Boardwalk. I ran up to the USS Midway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Reporting Craig Martin style</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/fim-reporting-craig-martin-style.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 12:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/fim-reporting-craig-martin-style.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks for attending the session, glad you liked i&amp;hellip; Craig Martin - May 2, 2012
Thanks for attending the session, glad you liked it! I had fun talking and running with Scissors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Reporting Craig Martin style</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/fim-reporting-craig-martin-style.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 12:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/05/fim-reporting-craig-martin-style.html</guid>
      <description>Craig’s session is on how to get data out from the FIM Service and FIM Sync with PowerShell and displaying it with SSRS, which he has dubbed Scissors!
Ok Craig we get it! You have even persuaded me that PowerShell is important! I have started writing scripts. SQL Server of course is still important.
Key is to hook up a pipeline from PowerShell to pass into his custom SSRS PowerShell Data Processing Extension (DPE).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 15:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</guid>
      <description>Can you use both declarative and non-declarative a&amp;hellip; yekolo - Aug 4, 2013
Can you use both declarative and non-declarative at the same time? Declarative for some attribute mappings and non declarative for others?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 15:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</guid>
      <description>Well I delivered my session FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative. During lunch they changed the location. But the room was packed by 5 min after I began (guessing about 45-50 people). Many familiar faces.
We had a rollicking good time. I presented how things worked with Classic and Declarative presented some findings and asked for other opinions. Boy did I receive them.
My basic conclusion is that Declarative can reduce the code used and in turn improve the maintainability of the FIM implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM R2 Showdown -- Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/01/fim-r2-showdown-classic-vs-declarative.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 10:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/01/fim-r2-showdown-classic-vs-declarative.html</guid>
      <description>Come join me at The Experts Conference 2012 in San Diego April 29 - May2 where I will be presenting:
FIM R2 Showdown — Classic vs. Declarative
Speaker: David Lundell
Is there room enough for both in this town? FIM 2010 R2 has two ways of accomplishing many tasks: Classic and Declarative. Attend this showdown to learn when to saddle up Classic vs. when to saddle up with Declarative Sync Rules and why.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 News</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/05/fim-2010-r2-news.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/05/fim-2010-r2-news.html</guid>
      <description>At Tech Ed Atlanta Brjann Brekkan and Mark Wahl discussed FIM 2010 R2 in a public forum – so here is a lot of info that is now in the public forum.
Mark covered the new items that will come out in R2:
Web Based Password reset (no need for a domain joined computer, no need to install Password Client no need for Active X, support for Firefox)
Although for integration with the GINA (the login screen) you still need to install the FIM Password Reset Client</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
