<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XML on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.com/tags/xml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XML on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:29:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.com/tags/xml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FIM Sets, XPATH, finding nulls with Strings</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/fim-sets-xpath-finding-nulls-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/fim-sets-xpath-finding-nulls-with.html</guid>
      <description>Watch out for the latest FIM hotfix. It appears i&amp;hellip; Chris Clayton - Nov 4, 2011
Watch out for the latest FIM hotfix. It appears it will treat the % as a literal rather than a SQL wildcard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Sets, XPATH, finding nulls with Strings</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/fim-sets-xpath-finding-nulls-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/fim-sets-xpath-finding-nulls-with.html</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I encountered some rather strange behavior of a Set vs. the XPATH query in FIM 2010.
Using the Export-FIMConfig with the -onlyBaseResources -CustomConfig switches I run the following query to see if there are any users without a DisplayName
/Person[not(starts-with(DisplayName,&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;))]
It showed 20
So then I created a set, called “~ People with no displayname”, with that as the custom filter. I checked it doesn&amp;rsquo;t violate any of the limitations listed in the Business Policy Modeling doc (which I must say is a pretty good doc)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pending Exports Report in ILM</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/07/pending-exports-report-in-ilm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 14:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/07/pending-exports-report-in-ilm.html</guid>
      <description>Hopefully this topic will stir up some excitement among those wondering how to query objects in the connector space. The technique I am about to explicate for you works for both exports and imports.
As many of you aware, my colleague and fellow ILM MVP Brad Turner created the community reporting pack for MIIS/ILM some time ago. This is a package of reports written in SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
