<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflow on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 13:39:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christmastime FIM/MIM Open Source WF Reviews</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2016/12/christmastime-fimmim-open-source-wf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 13:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2016/12/christmastime-fimmim-open-source-wf.html</guid>
      <description>Over the years since FIM was first beta&amp;rsquo;d as ILM2 we have seen some cool workflows be released to open source. This is my review of the workflows I can find that are open source. First let me salute everyone who has contributed to the FIM and MIM community with these big undertakings. That said I am trying to give guidance to my readers as to what is the most useful in various situations and so I will make specific recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another talented Ensynchian joins the blogosphere</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/02/another-talented-ensynchian-joins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 13:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/02/another-talented-ensynchian-joins.html</guid>
      <description>My colleague Joe Zamora, a talented developer, who has been instrumental in helping us advance our knowledge of custom workflows, has just launched his own blog: CShark.
His first post is on how to &amp;ldquo;Generate AccountName in ILM2 custom workflow activity&amp;rdquo; and it came in response to a question in the ILM 2 connect forum entitled: Custom Workflow Activity to Generate samAccountName.
Go Joe Go!
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a sprinkling of understanding Workflow in ILM 2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/09/sprinkling-of-understanding-workflow-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 17:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/09/sprinkling-of-understanding-workflow-in.html</guid>
      <description>Very nice David, I would also urge readers to chec&amp;hellip; Brad Turner - Sep 3, 2008
Very nice David, I would also urge readers to check out Mark Gabarra&amp;rsquo;s blog for information relating WF and ILM 2. I also hope that we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to goad our own Paul Divan into bringing his experiences to the blogosphere!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a sprinkling of understanding Workflow in ILM 2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/09/sprinkling-of-understanding-workflow-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 17:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/09/sprinkling-of-understanding-workflow-in.html</guid>
      <description>So by now all of you know that understanding Windows Workflow Foundation is going to be quite helpful in implementing ILM 2.
Having lived 9 of the last 12 months in Redmond, WA, I now understand a lot more about sprinkling
So I thought I would provide a sprinkling of understanding about Windows Workflow Foundation: a categorization of the built in workflows.
Category
Activity
Composite
Notes
Invoke Web Service
Conditional</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
