<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quest on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.com/tags/quest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quest on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:36:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.com/tags/quest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Virtualization and Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</guid>
      <description>Any chance of getting an online version of this talk? Paul - Apr 2, 2011
Any chance of getting an online version of this talk?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Virtualization and Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</guid>
      <description>I did a lunch time presentation in partnership with Jonathan Sander. We presented how we can use Quest VWorkspace and Quest One Identity Manager to build a corporate store (we code named it VIPER) to provide a dynamic desktop experience.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Real World organizations simplify Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/11/case-study-real-world-organizations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 16:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/11/case-study-real-world-organizations.html</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow morning at 8 AM PST I will be participating as a speaker in a webinar with Jonathan Sander from Quest.
http://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/22703 Successful identity and access management means different things to different organizations, but in almost every case, it requires complex, time-consuming, and expensive solutions. However, an ever-growing number of organizations have found a new way to achieve their identity and access management objectives simply, inexpensively, and powerfully.
In this webcast, identity and access management experts will discuss how organizations like yours have discovered and are implementing a simplified approach to identity and access management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Business Now with Identity Management &amp; Single-Sign-On (SSO)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 21:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</guid>
      <description>I think they can really help in a lot of ways. Acc&amp;hellip; Karl - Sep 4, 2011
I think they can really help in a lot of ways. Accelerate your business with the help of these factors. Thanks a lot for sharing.
business consultant</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Business Now with Identity Management &amp; Single-Sign-On (SSO)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 21:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</guid>
      <description>Jun 10, 2010
1:00 p.m. Eastern / 10:00 a.m. Pacific (60 minutes)
To Register follow this link
Christopher Yeich - Editor, Strategic Content - Ziff Davis Enterprise
David Lundell - Identity Management Practice Director, Ensynch | Microsoft Identity Management MVP
Jonathan Sander - IAM and Security Analyst - Quest Software
Has your business experienced identity theft, with unauthorized access to your systems, data, and/or trade secrets?
Have you lost business because your customers and/or employees didn’t have access when needed?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
