<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identity Management on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.com/tags/identity-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Identity Management on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:36:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.com/tags/identity-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wanted: Up and coming Cyber Security Professionals</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2020/06/wanted-up-and-coming-cyber-security.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2020/06/wanted-up-and-coming-cyber-security.html</guid>
      <description>Cyber Security &amp;ndash; Identity Management Implementer
Secure your identities against the dangers of the Cyber World, automate the repetitive, and empower your users!
Let&amp;rsquo;s
Shut the front door on the most obvious vector for Cyber-attacks Reduce the IT department&amp;rsquo;s compliance burden (SOX, HIPAA, FERPA, GLBA, ISO etc). Free IT people to do tasks that require more brain power By
Automating the drone-like work of managing user identities
Disabling accounts of terminated users</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing the old Directory Experts Conference? Try HIP!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/10/missing-old-directory-experts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 16:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/10/missing-old-directory-experts.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday, Nov 5th, and Tuesday the 6th I will be attending and speaking at the Hybrid Identity Protection (HIP) Conference in NYC. On Monday at 4 PM I will be giving an updated version of Top Lessons Learned from Disasters in Identity Management as well as a sneak peek of my new book, How to be an MVP in Life.
I am very excited to attend this conference. Thanks to Darren Mar-Elia and Micky Bresman at Semperis for putting it all together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Identity Conference 2018 - Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/05/european-identity-conference-2018_17.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 03:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/05/european-identity-conference-2018_17.html</guid>
      <description>Jet lag and other issues caught up with me the next day (Tuesday) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend any sessions :(
One thing I love is that most presentations including keynotes are only 20 min long so even when we get a terrible one &amp;ndash; we know it will be over soon. But most of the sessions were good and some were great!
My first Wednesday session was listening to Sebastian Goodrick of SUVA and Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Lessons from Disasters in Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/03/top-10-lessons-from-disasters-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 19:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/03/top-10-lessons-from-disasters-in.html</guid>
      <description>I will speak at Kuppinger Cole&amp;rsquo;s European Identity Conference on Top 10 Lessons from Disasters in Identity Management in May in Munich.
With great automation capability comes great responsibility! Come discuss and learn vital lessons gleaned from disasters in Identity Management.
So if you would like your disaster story to be considered for inclusion let me know. I would love to add to the stories.
This will be a fun interactive session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identiverse, Cloud Identity Summit</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/03/identiverse-cloud-identity-summit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 17:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2018/03/identiverse-cloud-identity-summit.html</guid>
      <description>Last summer I attended and spoke at the Cloud Identity Summit in Chicago. First big news: it was renamed to Identiverse and 2018 will be in Boston. As a consultant I have limited time to attend conferences and speak. So conferences have to be great. I do love this one, but in the interest of time, I will be skipping it this year in favor of speaking at the European Identity Conference in May 2018 in Munich, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Cloud Identity Summit 2017</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2017/03/speaking-at-cloud-identity-summit-2017.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 10:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2017/03/speaking-at-cloud-identity-summit-2017.html</guid>
      <description>I am excited to announce that I will be speaking at the Cloud Identity Summit 2017 in Chicago in June.
I will discuss How Identity Management (Employee and Consumer) affects the bottom line.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is MIM dead? Not yet!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2017/03/is-mim-dead-not-yet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2017/03/is-mim-dead-not-yet.html</guid>
      <description>From time to time I hear people wonder if MIM is dead.
Why do people ask?
They don&amp;rsquo;t feel like they have heard a good road map recently They aren&amp;rsquo;t seeing the improvements they hoped for They aren&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to the actions of the product group Why do I say it isn&amp;rsquo;t dead yet?
While the Cloud Identity is the future, we are and will be in hybrid identity for a long time and MIM is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s key component to that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check your inputs -- Save your job!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2016/02/check-your-inputs-save-your-job.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 15:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2016/02/check-your-inputs-save-your-job.html</guid>
      <description>At various times in my 10 years of Identity Management Consulting and 25 years working in the IT industry I have been asked to clean up various messes generated by those before me. Some of those messes involved disk failure or other issues that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be completely prevented. But some involved automated process that didn&amp;rsquo;t check their inputs.
If garbage into a computer gives you garbage out, then garbage into an automated process that doesn&amp;rsquo;t check its inputs gives you a meltdown!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Data needs Identity in order to Act</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/05/big-data-needs-identity-in-order-to-act.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 16:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/05/big-data-needs-identity-in-order-to-act.html</guid>
      <description>At the 2015 Identity Summit Scott McNeely declared &amp;ldquo;Big data without Identity is not actionable&amp;rdquo;
Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss.
Pulling from Information Week and IBM the Top 6 use cases of Big Data are:
1. Big Data Exploration
2. 360 degree view of customer
3. Information Security and Intelligence
4. Operation Analysis of data from Internet of Things
5. Data warehouse Augmentation/Optimization
6. Big Data Efficiency play (break down silos)
Big Data use case</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review of Home -- or how IDM could have saved the day.</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/04/movie-review-of-home-or-how-idm-could.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 08:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/04/movie-review-of-home-or-how-idm-could.html</guid>
      <description>Over the weekend I took one of my children to see the new animated film Home starring Jim Parsons, Rihanna, Steve Martin and Jennifer Lopez. A group of technically superior but very cowardly aliens, called the Boov flee from their implacable enemy, the Gorgs, and decide to take over Earth, relocating all of the primitive natives (us) to Australia. Aside from the political commentary of the entire human race being placed in a reservation, the thing that most struck me was how one of the near disasters could have been averted through solid Identity Management Systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow up #1 on How does Identity Management Impact the Bottom Line? Selling IDM</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/02/follow-up-1-on-how-does-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 09:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2015/02/follow-up-1-on-how-does-identity.html</guid>
      <description>In my presentation last week at #OCGUS15 The Redmond Summit put on by my friends at OCG, on &amp;ldquo;How does Identity Management Impact the Bottom Line? Selling IDM&amp;rdquo; I illustrated how understanding more about Financial statements such as Profit/Loss statements as well as Balance Sheets can be helpful. So here is a link to learn more:
•http://www.investopedia.com/articles/basics/06/financialreporting.asp
Among other things this is helpful to be able to articulate how your projects and programs can impact the bottom line such as how User provisioning/Deprovisioning impacts the Profit and Loss Statement:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistaken Identity</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2014/10/mistaken-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 12:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2014/10/mistaken-identity.html</guid>
      <description>Years ago, I walked into the client site a few months into an Identity Management project, and the PM told me his account had been deactivated by mistake as an employee with the same last name and same first initial was terminated, and they termed his account by mistake.
Ironic.
A few years before that I visited a client whose VP of HR had his account disabled when they let the janitor go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declarative or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</guid>
      <description>I see two challenges: 1. There is not feature pari&amp;hellip; Craig Martin - Oct 3, 2013
I see two challenges:
1. There is not feature parity between the two types of sync rules
2. The imperative support (VBA) in the new sync rules is limited and difficult to debug
My wish is that we had better extensibility in the new sync rules (scrap VBA, or figure out how to improve the extensibility and debugging).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declarative or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/10/declarative-or-bust.html</guid>
      <description>Michael Pearn from down under wrote about his experience trying to use just Declarative Sync Rules
His experience &amp;ndash; especially the religious debates are similar to my own. It made me recall my presentation at TEC 2012 the FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative
The vast majority of old hands at the presentation declared for Classic both before and after the presentation. During the presentation I attempted to view anything you could do without code as declarative whether it came from a sync rule or not, especially if it was a new feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive FIM and AD LDS project at DPDHL</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/02/massive-fim-and-ad-lds-project-at-dpdhl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 10:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2013/02/massive-fim-and-ad-lds-project-at-dpdhl.html</guid>
      <description>Watch the presentation that James Booth (who worked with us on the project) and Joe Gasowski (DPDHL) gave at the Redmond Identity Summit 2013 about our project at DHL to replace the DPDHL Sun One Directory and deploy FIM to replace both CriticalPath and a home-grown admin portal.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons to be thankful for Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/11/5-reasons-to-be-thankful-for-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 15:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/11/5-reasons-to-be-thankful-for-identity.html</guid>
      <description>On the eve of Thanksgiving I offer 5 reasons to be thankful for Identity Management (user provisioning, deprovisioning, group and role management, etc.):
What other compliance project can actually have a positive ROI? You get improved compliance (and the ability to show it) You also get better security as accounts are disabled quickly Then you save money through the automation Identity Management can help support your corporate goals You can empower users to serve themselves with password resets, group/role requests It can help keep your organization out of the shame columns in the trade rags We have all read about the disgruntled former employee accessing data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Best Practices Volume 1 has been updated for R2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 09:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</guid>
      <description>We have purchased to original copy, are we entitle&amp;hellip; FMustafa - Sep 2, 2012
We have purchased to original copy, are we entitled to get a free upgrade to R2 version??
This comment has been removed by the author.
Any tentative date for print edition
The print edition is already available.
Just downloaded the EBook version from Lulu. Would love to see this available in a Kindle (or other e-reader) edition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Best Practices Volume 1 has been updated for R2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 09:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/09/fim-best-practices-volume-1-has-been.html</guid>
      <description>Just this morning I have published the updated for R2 edition of FIM Best Practices Volume 1. Now called FIM R2 Best Practices Volume 1: Introduction, Architecture And Installation Of Forefront Identity Manager 2010 R2. The EBook edition is in color!
Print Edition of FIM R2 Best Practices Volume 1 is still B/W
Go to the lulu.com home page to get a coupon code for 20% off (offer expires 11:59 PM Sept 7 2012).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award for Me, Award for Insight</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 06:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on your renewal David! Henrik Nilsson - Jul 1, 2012
Congratulations on your renewal David!
Congratulations!!
Way to go man!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award for Me, Award for Insight</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 06:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/07/award-for-me-award-for-insight.html</guid>
      <description>What a good week – Insight was awarded Microsoft Desktop Partner of the Year, and I just received news of my MVP award in the Forefront Identity Management area has been renewed.
The Desktop Partner of the Year is a great accomplishment by our Systems Management and Virtualization practice. This one will be added to all of the awards we won as Ensynch:
As for the MVP, I am always honored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 Summary</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks David for a great overview of what was disc&amp;hellip; Henrik Nilsson - May 4, 2012
Thanks David for a great overview of what was discussed at TEC this year. I wish I could have attended but way too much work right now but I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to attend TEC Europe this year (if there&amp;rsquo;s gonna be any) and US next year.
Great to meet you David - thanks for the compliment ;) &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m one of those who&amp;rsquo;s been using your SQL scripts for years, and it was great to rub shoulders with so many bright people in this relatively small niche of ours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 Summary</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/tec-2012-summary.html</guid>
      <description>Wow TEC 2012 is already over and I am already back home. What a week!
The venue was great. San Diego is always a great place to be, cool yet not too cold. Right on the bay. Great hotel. The Marriot Marquis and Marinas has an awesome pool – went for a great swim on Monday night. Tuesday morning I really enjoyed a jog on the Boardwalk. I ran up to the USS Midway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look what I found in the news</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/look-what-i-found-in-news.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 07:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/05/look-what-i-found-in-news.html</guid>
      <description>I didn’t even know that Identity and Access Management (IAM) workers had a union!
Of course, imagine my disappointment to learn that it is International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers union.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 15:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</guid>
      <description>Can you use both declarative and non-declarative a&amp;hellip; yekolo - Aug 4, 2013
Can you use both declarative and non-declarative at the same time? Declarative for some attribute mappings and non declarative for others?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 15:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/fim-2010-r2-showdown-classic-vs.html</guid>
      <description>Well I delivered my session FIM 2010 R2 Showdown: Classic vs. Declarative. During lunch they changed the location. But the room was packed by 5 min after I began (guessing about 45-50 people). Many familiar faces.
We had a rollicking good time. I presented how things worked with Classic and Declarative presented some findings and asked for other opinions. Boy did I receive them.
My basic conclusion is that Declarative can reduce the code used and in turn improve the maintainability of the FIM implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does “no commitment” really mean?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/what-does-no-commitment-really-mean.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 21:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/04/what-does-no-commitment-really-mean.html</guid>
      <description>I recently received a mailer for YouFit Health Clubs, offering me “$1 down, $10 month with no commitment” for a club they opened near my house (limited to the first 125 to sign up).
Sounds good, but following the principle of caveat emptor (buyer beware), I always read the fine print. According to the “Billing for Monthly Dues” agreement you may “discontinue your Month-to-Month membership you may do so at any time with a payment of a twenty-five (25) dollar processing fee.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 -- Update Rollup 2 4.0.3606.2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/02/fim-2010-update-rollup-2-4036062.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 09:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2012/02/fim-2010-update-rollup-2-4036062.html</guid>
      <description>FIM 2010 Update Rollup 2 is now available. Download from here
Before blindly applying this update it is critical that you read the release notes, as XMA&amp;rsquo;s or ECMA&amp;rsquo;s may not run after the update. If you changed the MIISServer.exe.config file to tweak the FIM MA performance the update won&amp;rsquo;t replace your file. So you have to make some updates to it by hand. This is documented in the release notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Referenced by Other works and Sale at Lulu</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/11/referenced-by-other-works-and-sale-at.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 07:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/11/referenced-by-other-works-and-sale-at.html</guid>
      <description>I was pleasantly surprised today to find three other books, referencing FIM Best Practices Volume 1, which because of a Lulu Sale you can get at 25% off until 12/14/2011 Coupon Code: BUYMYBOOK305 Coupon expires December 14, 2011 $50 Max Savings. Of course today only 30% off, CYBERMONDAY305.
All three have an identical blurb about FIM and reference FIM Best Practices Volume 1 as additional material.
Title
Author
User Provisioning: High-impact Strategies - What You Need to Know: Definitions, Adoptions, Impact, Benefits, Maturity, Vendors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 call for papers open for 2 more days</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/11/experts-conference-call-for-papers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 10:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/11/experts-conference-call-for-papers.html</guid>
      <description>The Experts Conference Call for Papers still open until Nov 18th
http://www.theexpertsconference.com/us/2012/submit-a-paper/ For general info: http://www.theexpertsconference.com/us/2012/
I have attended at spoke at this conference since 2007. I love it. It is a great experience and loads of great in-depth technical training by top experts on Directory &amp;amp; Identity, as well as SharePoint, Exchange, Virtualization &amp;amp; Cloud and PowerShell Deep Dive. Also come and learn about the inside joke dealing with the rubber chicken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big news–Insight &#43; Ensynch</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/09/big-newsinsight-ensynch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 12:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/09/big-newsinsight-ensynch.html</guid>
      <description>Insight to acquire Ensynch.
As my colleague Rebecca Croft said:
We are very excited about the union of Insight and Ensynch and the benefits that it will bring to our clients. Both companies are focused on helping our clients find innovative, cost effective solutions to address business needs. Bringing Ensynch into the Insight organization will offer clients more robust software services, particularly around Microsoft Enterprise Agreements, as well as improved services delivery, enhanced virtualization and cloud capabilities and solution-focused approach to software sales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Extensible Management Agents That Scale (Rebecca Croft)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/06/sql-extensible-management-agents-that.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 15:27:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/06/sql-extensible-management-agents-that.html</guid>
      <description>Rebecca, a fellow Ensynchian, presented at TEC 2011 on the limitations of the standard out of the box SQL Management and how she overcame them by writing a very fast eXtensible Management Agent (XMA).
First attempt use ado.net sql reader to read data (really fast) and write one row at a time to the AVP file (but that gets slow when dealing with large data sets).
Second attempt use the T-SQL “FOR XML” clause to transform the data to XML and then use an XSLT to transform to LDIF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 R2 News</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/05/fim-2010-r2-news.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/05/fim-2010-r2-news.html</guid>
      <description>At Tech Ed Atlanta Brjann Brekkan and Mark Wahl discussed FIM 2010 R2 in a public forum – so here is a lot of info that is now in the public forum.
Mark covered the new items that will come out in R2:
Web Based Password reset (no need for a domain joined computer, no need to install Password Client no need for Active X, support for Firefox)
Although for integration with the GINA (the login screen) you still need to install the FIM Password Reset Client</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using FIM to manage BPOS/Office 365</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/using-fim-to-managing-bposoffice-365.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 10:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/using-fim-to-managing-bposoffice-365.html</guid>
      <description>Carol presented a solution to a very thorny problem – how to overcome the lack of delegation in BPOS. In BPOS a user is either an admin or a user. So she used FIM to provide the delegation. Very detailed, very complete solution. She illustrated some of the scripts she has posted on her blog such as http://www.wapshere.com/missmiis/a-script-to-create-sets-and-mprs-from-templates Well done Carol!
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 reporting using SQL Server Reporting Services (Jeremy and Craig)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-2010-reporting-using-sql-server.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 10:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-2010-reporting-using-sql-server.html</guid>
      <description>Link to Jeremy and Craig&amp;rsquo;s solution please? Sami - Jul 1, 2011
Link to Jeremy and Craig&amp;rsquo;s solution please?
http://www.identitytrench.com/2010/11/simple-reporting-in-fim-2010-with-ssrs.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 reporting using SQL Server Reporting Services (Jeremy and Craig)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-2010-reporting-using-sql-server.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 10:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-2010-reporting-using-sql-server.html</guid>
      <description>Jeremy and Craig had an interesting shoot out showing off their differing versions of reporting from FIM. Jeremy has an “agent” that he uses to pull the data out of FIM and store it in SQL, after which doing SSRS reports is not terribly difficult. Craig’s approach was to start off by creating a generic SSRS Data Processing extension for PowerShell, and then adjusted to pull data from FIM. Both approaches look very slick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud computing single sign-on. Making ADFS work with Google and Salesforce (Nikita Ryumin)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/cloud-computing-single-sign-on-making.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 10:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/cloud-computing-single-sign-on-making.html</guid>
      <description>This TEC session on the Directory Services track was short but sweet illustrating how to connect ADFS to Google and SalesForce.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Virtualization and Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</guid>
      <description>Any chance of getting an online version of this talk? Paul - Apr 2, 2011
Any chance of getting an online version of this talk?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Virtualization and Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/desktop-virtualization-and-identity.html</guid>
      <description>I did a lunch time presentation in partnership with Jonathan Sander. We presented how we can use Quest VWorkspace and Quest One Identity Manager to build a corporate store (we code named it VIPER) to provide a dynamic desktop experience.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Authentication Activities in FIM (Ikrima Elhassan)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/creating-authentication-activities-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/creating-authentication-activities-in.html</guid>
      <description>This session at TEC was quite interesting. Ikrima presented quite a lot of material about how to extend FIM with your own authentication activities, demonstrating a OTP password reset approach.
Code is available at https://github.com/ikrima/Public-Development
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recruiting</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/recruiting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/recruiting.html</guid>
      <description>Hey readers, our Identity Practice at Ensynch is keeping us very busy. We would like to have more Identity consultants as part of our team. Come work with me and the rest of our fantastically talented Identity Team.
We are looking for people with experience in Forefront Identity Manager 2010 and people with experience in ADFS 2.0. We are looking for both Full Time Employees as well as people interested in being contractors for us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing and Implementing RBAC Solutions with FIM 2010 Group Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/designing-and-implementing-rbac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/designing-and-implementing-rbac.html</guid>
      <description>After I introduced Brad Turner and turned the time over to him, he showed off some really cool FIM extensions to enable RBAC. He even showed how it fits the NIST RBAC definitions even through level 3.
The key design decision was to extend the Set and Group objects. The Set then functions as a role. This allows for both explicit and criteria based membership. A new object type for a Role Membership allows for the user’s membership in a role to expire at an individual time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Best Practices: Sizing Your FIM Installation</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-best-practices-sizing-your-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/fim-best-practices-sizing-your-fim.html</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of fun presenting this session. Largely based on chapter 5 in volume 1 I showed how to decide on your High availability approach, how that impacts your topology choice, and then how to estimate your scale, load, and complexity points. Then based on those factors figure out how big to make your SQL Server that hosts the FIM service database.
In the middle I did enjoy putting in a plug for our Ensynch sponsored green, dishwasher safe water bottles, as I took a drink of my fruit punch Gatorade mix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can PXEs Fly? FIM and SCCM Integration (Rob Allen)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/can-pxes-fly-fim-and-sccm-integration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 16:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/can-pxes-fly-fim-and-sccm-integration.html</guid>
      <description>I was looking forward to this one, but got called away. I hope to look at the slides soon.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Management Agents with the new EZMA (Andreas Kjellman)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/creating-management-agents-with-new.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/creating-management-agents-with-new.html</guid>
      <description>At TEC 2011, Andreas Kjellman of Microsoft, who “owns” the FIM synchronization engine, showed off the upcoming EZMA framework.
The problem:
The existing eXtensible Management Agent (XMA) does not have a call based import method, we are limited to using GUIDs as the initial anchors, and we don’t have partitions in an XMA.
Solution
EZMA – which, IMO, will actually be a little harder to do than an XMA but will allow the developer to do much more that will make the FIM admin’s life easier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Files, FIM, and PowerShell (James Booth)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/files-fim-and-powershell-james-booth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 11:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/files-fim-and-powershell-james-booth.html</guid>
      <description>James Booth former Microsoft Group Program Manager for MIIS (precursor to FIM) presented on using PowerShell to process files in preparation for consumption by FIM.
James points out that “In the beginning, it was all files.” These call based MA’s are the new kids on the block, also said that at Microsoft in 2000 the philosophy was “XML is the answer, now what is your question?”
James has posted his new commandlets to GitHub https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2011–FIM Workflows Deep dive</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/tec-2011fim-workflows-deep-dive.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 16:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/tec-2011fim-workflows-deep-dive.html</guid>
      <description>I am already in Las Vegas, prepping to assist my fellow Ensynch coworkers, Joe Zamora, and Rebecca Croft as they lead an awesome value packed pre-conference workshop tomorrow (Sunday) morning at 8 AM to 12 PM (noon). Jerry Camel and Brad Turner will also be around to assist.
There are so many good sessions to attend this time here are some of the ones I am looking forward to:
Monday morning gets the FIMsters off to a great start with a choice of two great sessions:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/making-sense-of-cloud.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 21:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/04/making-sense-of-cloud.html</guid>
      <description>National Roadshow Series: 2 High Value Sessions in 1 Business Focused Technology Briefing from Leading Industry Experts at Ensynch and Microsoft
It’s time to make sense of the plethora of rhetoric around the term &amp;ldquo;Cloud.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s time to cut through the hype and figure out how to leverage the latest Dynamic Private Cloud and Public Cloud technologies and provide real value to your business.
Why Attend?
Learn how organizations worldwide are realizing tremendous business value as they begin to migrate portions of their business to securely provide IT as a service through private and public cloud solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webinar: Cloud’s Silver Lining: Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/03/webinar-clouds-silver-lining-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/03/webinar-clouds-silver-lining-identity.html</guid>
      <description>Business Insights Webcast: The Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Silver Lining: Identity Management
Join Us for an Informative Webcast on the Value of IDA in the Cloud
- Part 2 in a Series of Webcasts from Microsoft FIM MVP David Lundell -
Identity Management is a critical component to realizing the true value of the Cloud.
Solutions from Microsoft including Forefront Identity Manager (FIM), Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS), and Microsoft Forefront Unified Access Gateway (Forefront UAG) allow you to get the most out of your cloud applications (such as Office 365, BPOS, and other Software a Service (SaaS) solutions); while enabling a seamless transition in managing the identities of your users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get FIM Training from Author of FIM Best Practices Volume 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/01/get-fim-training-from-author-of-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 09:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2011/01/get-fim-training-from-author-of-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Come get FIM training from David Lundell, FIM MVP and author of FIM Best Practices Volume 1.
Register by emailing FIMTraining@Ensynch.com, providing your contact info, which class and date you want to attend. You will then be contacted to complete the registration.
On Feb 8th - Feb 11th in downtown Phoenix (class will start at 8 AM), I will be teaching 50382A Implementing Forefront Identity Manager 2010 and of course adding in lots of valuable information from various FIM implementations that I have performed and supervised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law of Unintended Consequences</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/12/law-of-unintended-consequences.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/12/law-of-unintended-consequences.html</guid>
      <description>Any news on certification paths for IDM? Derek A. Hanson - Dec 6, 2010
Any news on certification paths for IDM?
Hey Derek,
No news yet. Just my own speculation but I would expect to see an exam covering several Microsoft Identity Technologies emerging sometime next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law of Unintended Consequences</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/12/law-of-unintended-consequences.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/12/law-of-unintended-consequences.html</guid>
      <description>In the process of setting up to teach 50382A - Implementing Forefront Identity Manager 2010 in Phoenix, AZ (Feb 8-11 and May 23 – May 26 – registration info to follow in a subsequent post) and looking at other courses in the Microsoft Courseware library I have noticed an interesting trend – most courses have lots of very bland reviews like this:
“Good Course”
“Good one”
“Good content and best practices”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Real World organizations simplify Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/11/case-study-real-world-organizations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 16:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/11/case-study-real-world-organizations.html</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow morning at 8 AM PST I will be participating as a speaker in a webinar with Jonathan Sander from Quest.
http://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/22703 Successful identity and access management means different things to different organizations, but in almost every case, it requires complex, time-consuming, and expensive solutions. However, an ever-growing number of organizations have found a new way to achieve their identity and access management objectives simply, inexpensively, and powerfully.
In this webcast, identity and access management experts will discuss how organizations like yours have discovered and are implementing a simplified approach to identity and access management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Errata and Updates to FIM Best Practices Volume 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/09/errata-and-updates-to-fim-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 07:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/09/errata-and-updates-to-fim-best.html</guid>
      <description>Could you post a complete listing of the correctio&amp;hellip; Keith Crosby - Sep 3, 2010
Could you post a complete listing of the corrections? In particular, the changes around the unattended client install. BTW, great job on Volume 1. I&amp;rsquo;m, looking forward to Volume 2 (and an eBook version would be great as well).
I love volume 1! Is it too soon to start asking about volume 2 :-)
Keith,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Errata and Updates to FIM Best Practices Volume 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/09/errata-and-updates-to-fim-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 07:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/09/errata-and-updates-to-fim-best.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks to several readers including Freek Berson, for catching a few errors I made while revising after my first round of reviewers.
Changes: in version 1.1 (Sept 28, 2010)
Chapter 1, updated the manager to director card, previously the word director was not visible (page 2)
Manager
Director
Chapter 1 Fixed “Error Missing Reference” in Chapter 1 (page 4) to refer to Figure 1-2 Actual Photo of Smart Card
Fixed client unattended install in Chapter 7: deleted reference to config files and corrected registry references.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book is here! FIM Best Practices Volume 1 is Available</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/08/book-is-here-fim-best-practices-volume.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 23:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/08/book-is-here-fim-best-practices-volume.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations!! I&amp;rsquo;ll order it immediately. Naohiro Fujie - Aug 1, 2010
Congratulations!!
I&amp;rsquo;ll order it immediately.
Congrats, any chance of an ebook?
Dan,
I considered the e-book route, but at least for the time being decided to go with a printed version. Feel free to lobby and persuade me why an ebook version would be better.
Thanks for the orders!
Ordered!
I was hoping there&amp;rsquo;d be an eBook for instant gratification and keyword search.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book is here! FIM Best Practices Volume 1 is Available</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/08/book-is-here-fim-best-practices-volume.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 23:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/08/book-is-here-fim-best-practices-volume.html</guid>
      <description>To purchase a copy of the book please follow this link. The best view to present from the lulu site is probably this one: http://www.lulu.com/spotlight/david_lundell as it has the brief description of the book and the author bio.
You also have the ability to preview a few parts of the book
The book came out to be 258 pages from cover to cover, and yes we included an index! By publishing it through Lulu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book: FIM Best Practices Volume 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/07/book-fim-best-practices-volume-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 17:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/07/book-fim-best-practices-volume-1.html</guid>
      <description>Hi David, any update on the availability date? Unknown - Aug 2, 2010
Hi David, any update on the availability date?
The day it&amp;rsquo;s out I&amp;rsquo;ll have my card ready!
Hi David, any news on the book? Hope your back is better!
The book is now available! My back is better too!
I have already placed my order and I am looking forward to getting the book in the mail.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book: FIM Best Practices Volume 1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/07/book-fim-best-practices-volume-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 17:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/07/book-fim-best-practices-volume-1.html</guid>
      <description>In two weeks we (Brad Turner is my co-author) will make available for ordering a book on FIM entitled:
FIM Best Practices Volume 1: Introduction, Architecture And Installation Of Forefront Identity Manager 2010
Information on order will be posted here on my blog
This will be the first book on Forefront Identity Manager in English that is not focused on Certificate Management (Brian Komar wrote on book on FIM Certificate Management deployment and two gentlemen from Japan wrote a book on FIM in Japanese as blogged about by fellow MVP, Naohiro Fujie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Overview Whitepaper on FIM released!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/technical-overview-whitepaper-on-fim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 19:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/technical-overview-whitepaper-on-fim.html</guid>
      <description>Technical overview whitepaper on FIM 2010 (download)
Brad and I spent many long hours writing this! Glad to see it come out in the long form. Thanks to the product group for the opportunity and the Brjann, Mark, and Markus for reviewing and editing it.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensynch’s Identity Practice -- Finalist for WPC Award</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/ensynchs-identity-practice-finalist-for.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 19:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/ensynchs-identity-practice-finalist-for.html</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has honored the efforts of our Identity and Secure Access Management Practice by making us a finalist for 2010 Partner of the Year, Core Infrastructure Solutions, Server Platform, as a result of our work with FIM, ILM, AD, AD FS and AD CS.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object reference not set to an instance of an object</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/object-reference-not-set-to-instance-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/object-reference-not-set-to-instance-of.html</guid>
      <description>/Remi - Nov 3, 2010
This comment has been removed by the author.
Hello David! :) Have you got the time to test this in a lab ?
I`am experiencing the same problem. And I`ve tried everything without any luck.
http://social.technet.microsoft.com/Forums/en/ilm2/thread/deae65d0-ede6-4b36-994b-3695d0cc8260</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object reference not set to an instance of an object</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/object-reference-not-set-to-instance-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/object-reference-not-set-to-instance-of.html</guid>
      <description>Lessons learned:
Run the Do a FIM MA account configuration quick test script.
Always refresh the schema of the FIM MA using the real FIM MA Service Account which we usually call svc-FIMMA.
Scenario:
You have just modified the schema of FIM Service by creating a new Boolean attribute and have bound it to the user resource type. You refresh the FIM Schema, select the new attribute setup a direct export attribute flow from the corresponding Boolean metaverse attribute to the FIM MA attribute.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Business Now with Identity Management &amp; Single-Sign-On (SSO)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 21:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</guid>
      <description>I think they can really help in a lot of ways. Acc&amp;hellip; Karl - Sep 4, 2011
I think they can really help in a lot of ways. Accelerate your business with the help of these factors. Thanks a lot for sharing.
business consultant</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Business Now with Identity Management &amp; Single-Sign-On (SSO)</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 21:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/06/accelerate-your-business-now-with.html</guid>
      <description>Jun 10, 2010
1:00 p.m. Eastern / 10:00 a.m. Pacific (60 minutes)
To Register follow this link
Christopher Yeich - Editor, Strategic Content - Ziff Davis Enterprise
David Lundell - Identity Management Practice Director, Ensynch | Microsoft Identity Management MVP
Jonathan Sander - IAM and Security Analyst - Quest Software
Has your business experienced identity theft, with unauthorized access to your systems, data, and/or trade secrets?
Have you lost business because your customers and/or employees didn’t have access when needed?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Register for TEC 2010 – hope to see you there</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/register-for-tec-2010-hope-to-see-you.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 17:34:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/register-for-tec-2010-hope-to-see-you.html</guid>
      <description>Register using this code to get a discount: ATESENSYNC
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2010 – Speaking and Sponsoring</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/tec-2010-speaking-and-sponsoring.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/tec-2010-speaking-and-sponsoring.html</guid>
      <description>I am super excited about speaking at The Experts Conference 2010 (I also spoke at Directory Experts in ‘07, and ‘08 as well as last year’s The Experts Conference). Register using this code to get a discount: ATESENSYNC
Once more Ensynch is sponsoring TEC but this year we are a gold sponsor for TEC 2010.
Here is the lineup of Ensynch Speakers at The Experts Conference (also see Brad Turner’s take on our new speakers)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM 2010 RTM Today!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/fim-2010-rtm-today.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 13:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/03/fim-2010-rtm-today.html</guid>
      <description>Today, March 2, at the RSA conference Microsoft announced the release to manufacturing of Forefront Identity Manager 2010 (FIM, formerly codenamed ILM “2”) with General Availability starting next month.
Download the eval here:
Microsoft® Forefront™ Identity Manager 2010 Evaluation Version
Yeah!
FIM gives us capabilities for User provisioning (and deprovisioning), Group management, Self-Service Password Reset, Password Synchronization, Workflows with Approvals, User profile self-service management, and accomplishing these items through Declarative Provisioning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final Update for FIM RC1 released</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/02/final-update-for-fim-rc1-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 10:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/02/final-update-for-fim-rc1-released.html</guid>
      <description>On Friday the product group released Update 3 for Forefront Identity Manager 2010 RC1 available through connect
https://connect.microsoft.com/site433/Downloads
Major changes as part of Update 3 (my regurgitation and comments from the release notes):
Fewer trips to the FIM Service event log – since the FIM MA export errors will now show up in the Synchronization Service Manager! Hallelujah! Less need for custom old style code Now more than 1 MA can be authoritative for deleting an object (resource) New functions for Sync Rules (Declarative Provisioning) – I guess I will have to update my function cheatsheet Null – not certain what they mean by this – null out the value or let another sync rule provide the value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM Hand on Labs</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/02/fim-hand-on-labs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 01:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2010/02/fim-hand-on-labs.html</guid>
      <description>More Hands on Labs for Forefront Identity Manager will be coming up (similar to the one I did in Irvine, CA) – Phoenix April 7th and 8th and then Dallas sometime in May.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM RCDC explained in brief</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/fim-rcdc-explained-in-brief.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/fim-rcdc-explained-in-brief.html</guid>
      <description>In this post I attempt to give you the reader a quick overview of how the FIM RCDC works conceptually. As for the mechanics of modifying the RCDC the nearly complete but growing collection of documents downloadable from MSFT will suffice.
As you will recall FIM is the new abbreviation for ILM, since it has been renamed Forefront Identity Manager, and RCDC is the Resource Control Display Configuration formerly known as the Object Visualization Configuration (OVC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Answering my FIM RC 1 question</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/answering-my-fim-rc-1-question.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 09:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/answering-my-fim-rc-1-question.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Darryl Russi for answering my questions in my earlier post An Update to FIM RC1 where I was asked about something I had read in the release notes:
Some of those items raise a few questions, like how to setup a FIM service that only takes requests from the sync service? Do we setup multiple FIM Service instances and then configure the FIM MA to talk to one of them, and not make that one available to web clients?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Synchronization FIM 2010 HOL Irvine California</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/identity-synchronization-fim-2010-hol.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 17:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/identity-synchronization-fim-2010-hol.html</guid>
      <description>I will be at the Microsoft Technical Center in Irvine on Dec 1 and 2 presenting this HOL with Marvin Tansley of Gemalto.
Identity Synchronization – Hands on Training
****
Date: December 1-2, 2009
Location: 3 Park Plaza, Suite 1800 Irvine, CA 92614 949-263-3000
Microsoft, Gemalto and Ensynch invite you to a free 2-day training seminar and hands-on-lab on Microsoft’s Forefront Lifecycle Manager (FIM 2010).
Come and learn how FIM 2010 can help you by delivering simplicity, agility and efficiency while increasing security and compliance within your enterprise identity infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Update to FIM RC1</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/update-to-fim-rc1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 23:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/11/update-to-fim-rc1.html</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has posted an update to FIM RC 1, dated Nov 6.
It looks like this update covers pretty much everywhere except Certificate Services (sorry Brian and Paul).
The Release notes included in the download lists the follow improvements:
Query and Sets
Resolved a number of issues that resulted in incorrect dynamic set membership.
Removed support for the use of the != operator with multivalued attributes. Xpath equality expressions on multivalued attributes must use the not() function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Password Reset?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/10/password-reset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 20:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/10/password-reset.html</guid>
      <description>How would you feel if this was the only barrier between the hacker and your data – a single password reset question? Just one!
I won’t tell you who this is since then you’ll just want to go after my data on that site.
Oh well. The barn door won’t be shut until the wolf has gotten into the sheep
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensynch The Place to Be</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/04/ensynch-place-to-be.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 07:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/04/ensynch-place-to-be.html</guid>
      <description>In the last four months two very talented people have joined Ensynch, Chris Calderon, ILM MVP, and Mark Struck.
Chris Calderon of IdentityJunkie.com fame is extremely talented with ILM, AD Federated Services (AD FS) and many other tools.
Mark Struck, is a very talented developer, and experienced implementer of ILM. Even before Mark joined the team he and I collaborated to figure out how to use the ILM 2 web services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few excellent Live@edu (Outlook Live) Blogs</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/04/few-excellent-liveedu-outlook-live.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 12:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/04/few-excellent-liveedu-outlook-live.html</guid>
      <description>I have been involved with the Microsoft Live@edu (formerly Windows Live@edu) and the Outlook Live (formerly Exchange Labs) programs for quite sometime.
What a wonderful opportunity for schools to alleviate the cost of hosting email for students and then to be able to offer it to alumni helping provide them with lifelong connection to the university and way to keep their email address from their student days. Maintaining stronger ties leads to more evangelism on the school&amp;rsquo;s behalf and will lead to more Alumni donations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Certificate and Identity Blogger on the Loose</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/new-certificate-and-identity-blogger-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 11:34:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/new-certificate-and-identity-blogger-on.html</guid>
      <description>Marc Mac Donnell has just launched his blog on http://assurancesinidentity.blogspot.com/ and called it Assurances in Identity, and has posted the links to the CLM API documentation and case study about some work he did with MCS UK and CapGemini.
I look forward to many more posts from Mark about some of the wizardry and trick in managing certificates and identities.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posted: ILM 2 Business Value webinar recording</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/posted-ilm-2-business-value-webinar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/posted-ilm-2-business-value-webinar.html</guid>
      <description>ILM 2 Business Value Webinar Recording
It has actually been posted for some time now, I have just been a bit busy (apology to my readers).
Other items will also get posted here in the column on the right hand side:
http://ensynch.com/pa_ci_identity_and_access_management.aspx
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netpro DEC -&gt; Quest TEC -- Ensynch&#39;s Sessions</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/netpro-dec-quest-tec-ensynch-sessions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 12:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/03/netpro-dec-quest-tec-ensynch-sessions.html</guid>
      <description>Back in business school we always studied name changes and rebranding, and this one has been interesting
Last summer NetPro deciding to expand the Directory Experts Conference (DEC) to include an exchange conference and so they re-branded the conference NetPro&amp;rsquo;s The Experts Conference. Then Quest acquired NetPro, so it became a completely re-branded conference as Quest&amp;rsquo;s The Expert Conference. So NetPro DEC became Quest TEC.
Sunday Mar 22nd - Wed Mar 25th in Vegas www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Identity Lifecycle Manager 2, Ask the experts</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/01/whats-new-in-identity-lifecycle-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 12:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2009/01/whats-new-in-identity-lifecycle-manager.html</guid>
      <description>Brad Turner and I are putting on a webinar on ILM 2.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Problems and their Technical Roots</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-and-their-technical.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 17:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-and-their-technical.html</guid>
      <description>Business Problem
Possible Underlying Business Problem
Cause
Technical Cause
Business launches a strategic initiative late
Employees don&amp;rsquo;t receive communications that they should
Don&amp;rsquo;t have email accounts
Aren&amp;rsquo;t in the right distribution lists
Lack of automated distribution list management and self service fulfillment
Employee can&amp;rsquo;t fulfill a customer order
Employees don&amp;rsquo;t have access to resources
Accounts haven&amp;rsquo;t been provisioned to the systems they need
Aren&amp;rsquo;t member of the groups or roles they need</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Problems VS Technical Problems</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 17:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</guid>
      <description>I like how you linked business problems to technic&amp;hellip; William Wagner - Sep 4, 2011
I like how you linked business problems to technical problems. I think they affect each other in a lot of ways. You always need to balance them so you can succeed.
form an llc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Problems VS Technical Problems</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 17:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</guid>
      <description>A business problem is when employees can&amp;rsquo;t execute their job duties in an efficient fashion. In fact sometimes they are unable to complete the tasks at all. Business problems are especially costly when they directly affect customers. These problems can cause cash flowing into the company to be delayed as a customer waits to place an order, or to receive goods (and hence to pay), they can cause revenue to be lost as a customer temporarily takes their business to a competitor or a finds a substitute, sometimes this leads to customers forming new business relationships and loss of all future revenue from that customer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 and 1/2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 03:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</guid>
      <description>A few days after my post about setting up the ILM 2 Web Service reference Joe Schulman and others from the ILM product group began a new blog designed to fill in the gaps in the knowledge in the community about how to use the web services. So far the blog looks great and is a welcome addition to my knowledge and the communities knowledge base! Great job Joe and Company and thanks for the link to my blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 The Service Reference</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 10:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</guid>
      <description>Does ILM open SOAP interfaces native? So that dev&amp;hellip; RobertW - Mar 4, 2009
Does ILM open SOAP interfaces native? So that developers who are simply looking for a .wsdl file to build their client can get up and running quickly.
not exactly you need to use the WCF approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 The Service Reference</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 10:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</guid>
      <description>Together, Mark Struck of Ipseity Inc and I, have figured out (after much beating of our heads against brick walls) how to use the ILM 2 Enumeration Endpoint to perform some basic reporting. (I figured out how to send the enumeration and get a response and then Mark figured out how to correctly form the pull messages so as to be able to retrieve the actual objects &amp;ndash; teamwork at its finest).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDM in pop culture</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/08/idm-in-pop-culture.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/08/idm-in-pop-culture.html</guid>
      <description>Some days I am amazed at how deeply the identity management concepts have penetrated into popular culture:
&amp;ldquo;Mr Big Stuff, who do you think you are?&amp;rdquo; clearly relates to an authentication issue or authorization issue.
&amp;ldquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t get fooled again&amp;rdquo; by the WHO is clearly making a reference to a Certificate Revocation List, now that I have revoked your certificate you won&amp;rsquo;t be authenticated again.
One area where pop culture is still shockingly uninformed still need help is in asset protection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Ed -- Lotsa Buzz ILM 2 and CLM</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/06/tech-ed-lotsa-buzz-ilm-2-and-clm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 16:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/06/tech-ed-lotsa-buzz-ilm-2-and-clm.html</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday Bob Muglia made a big announcement &amp;ndash; ILM 2 Beta 3 has been released. While the beta install is only 64 bit on Microsoft Connect you can download the 32-bit Virtual PC. At the ILM 2 booth at Tech Ed the Microsoft ILM Product Group and I were handing them out like crazy.
Thanks to Nima for inviting me to participate at the booth.
Best session I went was by Candy Stark from MS IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Unified Demo of Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/05/grand-unified-demo-of-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 13:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.com/2008/05/grand-unified-demo-of-identity.html</guid>
      <description>As I was architecting and assembling the Identity All Up workshop (part of the 2008 Directory Experts Conference see the review by Felix Gaehtgens, an analyst for Kuppinger Cole) designed to expose the attendees (or delegates) to all facets of the Microsoft Identity Access Platform, Lori Craw, from Microsoft referred to this as the &amp;ldquo;Grand Unified Demo&amp;rdquo;. I chuckled, instantly catching the reference to the still undiscovered Grand Unified Field theory that eluded Einstein and even today&amp;rsquo;s theoretical physicists.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
