<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 08:45:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is the Password dead? Gotta eat what you kill!</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/07/is-password-dead-gotta-eat-what-you-kill.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2013/07/is-password-dead-gotta-eat-what-you-kill.html</guid>
      <description>At last year&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Identity Summit in Vail I heard a lot about how the password is dead. I expect to hear a lot more this year.
Most of it fit into one of several categories:
Complaints about why passwords should be dead
In other words all of the various problems with passwords &amp;ndash; and there are
Schemes to have various applications depend on someone else&amp;rsquo;s password
While this is helpful it doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill the password</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIM R2 Showdown -- Classic vs. Declarative</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/01/fim-r2-showdown-classic-vs-declarative.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 10:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/01/fim-r2-showdown-classic-vs-declarative.html</guid>
      <description>Come join me at The Experts Conference 2012 in San Diego April 29 - May2 where I will be presenting:
FIM R2 Showdown — Classic vs. Declarative
Speaker: David Lundell
Is there room enough for both in this town? FIM 2010 R2 has two ways of accomplishing many tasks: Classic and Declarative. Attend this showdown to learn when to saddle up Classic vs. when to saddle up with Declarative Sync Rules and why.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEC 2012 call for papers open for 2 more days</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/11/experts-conference-call-for-papers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 10:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/11/experts-conference-call-for-papers.html</guid>
      <description>The Experts Conference Call for Papers still open until Nov 18th
http://www.theexpertsconference.com/us/2012/submit-a-paper/ For general info: http://www.theexpertsconference.com/us/2012/
I have attended at spoke at this conference since 2007. I love it. It is a great experience and loads of great in-depth technical training by top experts on Directory &amp;amp; Identity, as well as SharePoint, Exchange, Virtualization &amp;amp; Cloud and PowerShell Deep Dive. Also come and learn about the inside joke dealing with the rubber chicken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/04/making-sense-of-cloud.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 21:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2011/04/making-sense-of-cloud.html</guid>
      <description>National Roadshow Series: 2 High Value Sessions in 1 Business Focused Technology Briefing from Leading Industry Experts at Ensynch and Microsoft
It’s time to make sense of the plethora of rhetoric around the term &amp;ldquo;Cloud.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s time to cut through the hype and figure out how to leverage the latest Dynamic Private Cloud and Public Cloud technologies and provide real value to your business.
Why Attend?
Learn how organizations worldwide are realizing tremendous business value as they begin to migrate portions of their business to securely provide IT as a service through private and public cloud solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADFS v.2 shipped</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2010/05/adfs-v2-shipped.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 15:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2010/05/adfs-v2-shipped.html</guid>
      <description>Active Directory Federation Services v2 Ships!
This is awesome stuff – with ADFS v2 we can help you setup SSO with your SaaS vendors.
Here is an example that has been rendered generic.
ADFS 2.0 supports SAML 2.0 (the idp lite profile and rdp lite profile) which opens up many federation doors and WIF allows us to write custom security token services (sts) just in case the idp lite and rdp lite profile support isn’t up to handling the interaction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H30, Geneva Cola, Sitrus and Orange Fizz</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/h30-geneva-cola-sitrus-and-orange-fizz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 22:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/h30-geneva-cola-sitrus-and-orange-fizz.html</guid>
      <description>Back in business school I was a connoisseur of fine commercials. Recently I watched a commercial for Lipton Ice Tea (note I am a teetotaler who doesn&amp;rsquo;t drink tea) and I have to admire their cleverness in coming up with names for competitor products (see the title) in their &amp;ldquo;Lipton Tea, I think I love you&amp;rdquo; commercial. (Lyrics here)
Really the names are clever although the best is the H30 &amp;ndash; I just love it, a chemical compound that as far as I can tell can&amp;rsquo;t exist, but we all know they are making fun of flavored water.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
