<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Services on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/web-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Services on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 03:49:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 and 1/2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 03:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</guid>
      <description>A few days after my post about setting up the ILM 2 Web Service reference Joe Schulman and others from the ILM product group began a new blog designed to fill in the gaps in the knowledge in the community about how to use the web services. So far the blog looks great and is a welcome addition to my knowledge and the communities knowledge base! Great job Joe and Company and thanks for the link to my blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 The Service Reference</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 10:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</guid>
      <description>Does ILM open SOAP interfaces native? So that dev&amp;hellip; RobertW - Mar 4, 2009
Does ILM open SOAP interfaces native? So that developers who are simply looking for a .wsdl file to build their client can get up and running quickly.
not exactly you need to use the WCF approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 The Service Reference</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 10:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/11/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-service.html</guid>
      <description>Together, Mark Struck of Ipseity Inc and I, have figured out (after much beating of our heads against brick walls) how to use the ILM 2 Enumeration Endpoint to perform some basic reporting. (I figured out how to send the enumeration and get a response and then Mark figured out how to correctly form the pull messages so as to be able to retrieve the actual objects &amp;ndash; teamwork at its finest).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
