<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MBA on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/mba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MBA on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 09:01:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/mba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Follow up #1 on How does Identity Management Impact the Bottom Line? Selling IDM</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/02/follow-up-1-on-how-does-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 09:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2015/02/follow-up-1-on-how-does-identity.html</guid>
      <description>In my presentation last week at #OCGUS15 The Redmond Summit put on by my friends at OCG, on &amp;ldquo;How does Identity Management Impact the Bottom Line? Selling IDM&amp;rdquo; I illustrated how understanding more about Financial statements such as Profit/Loss statements as well as Balance Sheets can be helpful. So here is a link to learn more:
•http://www.investopedia.com/articles/basics/06/financialreporting.asp
Among other things this is helpful to be able to articulate how your projects and programs can impact the bottom line such as how User provisioning/Deprovisioning impacts the Profit and Loss Statement:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix area part-time MBA program comparisons at public universities</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/phoenix-area-part-time-mba-program.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 16:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/phoenix-area-part-time-mba-program.html</guid>
      <description>If you want to study for an Master in Business Adm&amp;hellip; way2 college - Apr 3, 2014
If you want to study for an Master in Business Administration (MBA) while still having time for a full time job, the finest way that you could achieve this is to study in an mba distance learning course.
Distance learning is the best mode of education for the professionals and for the people who cannot attend the college regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix area part-time MBA program comparisons at public universities</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/phoenix-area-part-time-mba-program.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 16:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2012/04/phoenix-area-part-time-mba-program.html</guid>
      <description>Even though I already have the MBA from Eller College at the U of A I recently put together the following analysis for a friend comparing the MBA options in Phoenix from U of A and ASU.
Eller College of Management
(University of Arizona) Evening
Eller College of Management
(University of Arizona) Executive
WP Carey School of Business (ASU) Professional Evening
WP Carey School of Business (ASU) Professional Weekend
ASU Executive</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
