<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLM on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/clm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLM on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 11:12:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/clm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To PKI or not to PKI?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/to-pki-or-not-to-pki.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 11:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/to-pki-or-not-to-pki.html</guid>
      <description>Hey Dave, I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice your blog before. Go&amp;hellip; Unknown - Jun 0, 2009
Hey Dave, I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice your blog before. Good work. Gimme a call&amp;hellip; Lets have lunch sometime soon. It would be nice to see you.
justin harris
justin@jwheel.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To PKI or not to PKI?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/to-pki-or-not-to-pki.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 11:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/06/to-pki-or-not-to-pki.html</guid>
      <description>When should one implement a Public Key Infrastructure and when should one not? Obviously we implement a PKI to solve a problem, usually around security, enabling secure communications with a web server, multi-factor authentication, encryption. A PKI solution can be very versatile, but it comes at a price in setup and maintenance. But what alternatives do we have? Let&amp;rsquo;s examine each problem in turn
Problem
PKI difficulties
Alternatives
Benefits for Alternatives</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Certificate and Identity Blogger on the Loose</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/new-certificate-and-identity-blogger-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 11:34:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/new-certificate-and-identity-blogger-on.html</guid>
      <description>Marc Mac Donnell has just launched his blog on http://assurancesinidentity.blogspot.com/ and called it Assurances in Identity, and has posted the links to the CLM API documentation and case study about some work he did with MCS UK and CapGemini.
I look forward to many more posts from Mark about some of the wizardry and trick in managing certificates and identities.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDM in pop culture</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/08/idm-in-pop-culture.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/08/idm-in-pop-culture.html</guid>
      <description>Some days I am amazed at how deeply the identity management concepts have penetrated into popular culture:
&amp;ldquo;Mr Big Stuff, who do you think you are?&amp;rdquo; clearly relates to an authentication issue or authorization issue.
&amp;ldquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t get fooled again&amp;rdquo; by the WHO is clearly making a reference to a Certificate Revocation List, now that I have revoked your certificate you won&amp;rsquo;t be authenticated again.
One area where pop culture is still shockingly uninformed still need help is in asset protection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Ed -- Lotsa Buzz ILM 2 and CLM</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/06/tech-ed-lotsa-buzz-ilm-2-and-clm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 16:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/06/tech-ed-lotsa-buzz-ilm-2-and-clm.html</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday Bob Muglia made a big announcement &amp;ndash; ILM 2 Beta 3 has been released. While the beta install is only 64 bit on Microsoft Connect you can download the 32-bit Virtual PC. At the ILM 2 booth at Tech Ed the Microsoft ILM Product Group and I were handing them out like crazy.
Thanks to Nima for inviting me to participate at the booth.
Best session I went was by Candy Stark from MS IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Unified Demo of Identity Management</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/05/grand-unified-demo-of-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 13:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/05/grand-unified-demo-of-identity.html</guid>
      <description>As I was architecting and assembling the Identity All Up workshop (part of the 2008 Directory Experts Conference see the review by Felix Gaehtgens, an analyst for Kuppinger Cole) designed to expose the attendees (or delegates) to all facets of the Microsoft Identity Access Platform, Lori Craw, from Microsoft referred to this as the &amp;ldquo;Grand Unified Demo&amp;rdquo;. I chuckled, instantly catching the reference to the still undiscovered Grand Unified Field theory that eluded Einstein and even today&amp;rsquo;s theoretical physicists.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
