<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ILM 2 RC0 on Identity Managed</title>
    <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/ilm-2-rc0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ILM 2 RC0 on Identity Managed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 14:54:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/tags/ilm-2-rc0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with the ILM 2 RC 0 Cert in Windows server 2003 domain</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/dealing-with-ilm-2-rc-0-cert-in-windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 14:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/dealing-with-ilm-2-rc-0-cert-in-windows.html</guid>
      <description>The Password Reset instructions ask us to use Group Policy to distribute the cert to the clients. This only works in Windows Server 2008 functional level domains. In Windows Server 2003 domains you can automate this using cerutil.exe
The following command will export the cert generated by ILM 2 install to the ilm2cert.cer file in the working directory
certutil -store trustedpeople IdentityLifeCycleManager2 ilm2cert.cer
This command can be used to import the cert from the command line</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems with Sync Rules in ILM 2 RC0 (err FIM RC0)?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/problems-with-sync-rules-in-ilm-2-rc0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 18:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/problems-with-sync-rules-in-ilm-2-rc0.html</guid>
      <description>If you will take a look at FIM(ILM) connections sc&amp;hellip; Unknown - Apr 2, 2009
If you will take a look at FIM(ILM) connections schema you will see that ILM MA has a direct SQL connectivity to FIM database (not through web service). As far as I know any change to metaverse schema fires up synchronization of this change to FIM database directly through SQL connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems with Sync Rules in ILM 2 RC0 (err FIM RC0)?</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/problems-with-sync-rules-in-ilm-2-rc0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 18:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/problems-with-sync-rules-in-ilm-2-rc0.html</guid>
      <description>Well I had a problem with a recent install &amp;ndash; the Metaverse Object Type Dropdown list was empty!
Turns out the source of this drop down list is the mv-data object type. However my install didn&amp;rsquo;t have this object. Obviously something was wrong. How does one create this object in the first place? Not directly in the portal. I am not certain when this object is supposed to be created. Install time?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM FIM Webinar Custom Workflow -- Joe Zamora</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/ilm-fim-webinar-custom-workflow-joe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 11:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/ilm-fim-webinar-custom-workflow-joe.html</guid>
      <description>Joe Zamora the maintainer of the Ensynch ILM 2 Custom Workflow Walkthrough is our main presenter at our next Webinar this Thursday at 9 AM Pacific. To register click on the image below. The code from our Pre-con workshop is posted on CodePlex Ensynch Custom WF Activities
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install ILM 2 in a SharePoint Farm</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/install-ilm-2-in-sharepoint-farm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 17:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/install-ilm-2-in-sharepoint-farm.html</guid>
      <description>As I endeavored to install the ILM 2 Portal into a SharePoint farm (WSS 3.0 SP 1) with a remote database I encountered the following problem:
The dreaded Premature Failure during installation.
When I turned on logging for the install and examined the file, I found:
Action 14:55:25: ConfigPortalAnonymousAccess.
CAQuietExec: CAQuietExec: This operation can be performed only on a computer that is joined to a server farm by users who have permissions in SQL Server to read from the configuration database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in name? Forefront Identity Manager 2010</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/what-in-name-forefront-identity-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 17:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/what-in-name-forefront-identity-manager.html</guid>
      <description>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard Zoomit VIA or rather Microsoft MetaDirectory Services has been renamed yet again, from Microsoft Identity Integration Server 2003 to Identity Lifecycle Manager 2007 to Forefront Identity Manager 2010 or FIM for short. For obvious reasons the L was dropped when the F was added (Forefront + ILM = FILM).
So ILM 2 =&amp;gt; FIM 2010 (stole this graphic from Brad Turner&amp;rsquo;s blog &amp;ndash; his Smart Art creations are beautiful &amp;ndash; recently I have been studying smart art under his tutelage I hope to soon approach his level of skill)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensynch The Place to Be</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/ensynch-place-to-be.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 07:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/04/ensynch-place-to-be.html</guid>
      <description>In the last four months two very talented people have joined Ensynch, Chris Calderon, ILM MVP, and Mark Struck.
Chris Calderon of IdentityJunkie.com fame is extremely talented with ILM, AD Federated Services (AD FS) and many other tools.
Mark Struck, is a very talented developer, and experienced implementer of ILM. Even before Mark joined the team he and I collaborated to figure out how to use the ILM 2 web services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MSIT&#39;s implementation of ILM 2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/msit-implementation-of-ilm-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/msit-implementation-of-ilm-2.html</guid>
      <description>TEC 2009 continues onto the last day.
Joel Silver spoke on his efforts and plans to implement ILM 2 for Microsoft. He presented a very interesting workflow to show how he addressed the challenge of creating unique email aliases.
Then I listened to Felix as he discussed some of the interesting aspects of LDAP enhancements from around the vendorscape (I think I just made that word up).
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posted: ILM 2 Business Value webinar recording</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/posted-ilm-2-business-value-webinar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/posted-ilm-2-business-value-webinar.html</guid>
      <description>ILM 2 Business Value Webinar Recording
It has actually been posted for some time now, I have just been a bit busy (apology to my readers).
Other items will also get posted here in the column on the right hand side:
http://ensynch.com/pa_ci_identity_and_access_management.aspx
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netpro DEC -&gt; Quest TEC -- Ensynch&#39;s Sessions</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/netpro-dec-quest-tec-ensynch-sessions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 12:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/03/netpro-dec-quest-tec-ensynch-sessions.html</guid>
      <description>Back in business school we always studied name changes and rebranding, and this one has been interesting
Last summer NetPro deciding to expand the Directory Experts Conference (DEC) to include an exchange conference and so they re-branded the conference NetPro&amp;rsquo;s The Experts Conference. Then Quest acquired NetPro, so it became a completely re-branded conference as Quest&amp;rsquo;s The Expert Conference. So NetPro DEC became Quest TEC.
Sunday Mar 22nd - Wed Mar 25th in Vegas www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another talented Ensynchian joins the blogosphere</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/02/another-talented-ensynchian-joins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 13:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/02/another-talented-ensynchian-joins.html</guid>
      <description>My colleague Joe Zamora, a talented developer, who has been instrumental in helping us advance our knowledge of custom workflows, has just launched his own blog: CShark.
His first post is on how to &amp;ldquo;Generate AccountName in ILM2 custom workflow activity&amp;rdquo; and it came in response to a question in the ILM 2 connect forum entitled: Custom Workflow Activity to Generate samAccountName.
Go Joe Go!
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Identity Lifecycle Manager 2, Ask the experts</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/whats-new-in-identity-lifecycle-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 12:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/whats-new-in-identity-lifecycle-manager.html</guid>
      <description>Brad Turner and I are putting on a webinar on ILM 2.
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Functions Explained</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-explained.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 13:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-explained.html</guid>
      <description>Excellent post David, thanks for putting this toge&amp;hellip; Brad Turner - Jan 3, 2009
Excellent post David, thanks for putting this together!
To remove bit #2 shouldn&amp;rsquo;t you use BitAnd(-3,userAccountControl) ?
Paolo is correct in pointing out that the numbers I calculated for masks are wrong. I did 32-bit numbers and tested it back on the 32-bit version of the ILM 2 Beta 3 VM. The calcs should be done using 64-bit as explained here: Using FIM to enable or disable accounts in Active Directory (http://social.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Functions Explained</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-explained.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 13:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-explained.html</guid>
      <description>Function Name
Parameters
David&amp;rsquo;s Description
Example
Example Explanation
BitAnd
mask
Type: Integer
flag
Type: Integer
BitAnd is a bitwise operation anding mask and flag. So if Flag is the UserAccountControl Attribute in AD and mask is negative 2147483645 (the two&amp;rsquo;s complement of 2) Then the result is that the disable bit (bit 2) is turned off leaving all of the other bits unchanged.
BitAnd can be combined with Eq to detect if a bit is set</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Functions all in one place</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-all-in-one-place.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 15:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2009/01/ilm-2-functions-all-in-one-place.html</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find in the ILM 2 RC 0 documentation anyplace that listed all of the functions available to you in sync rules and action workflows so here they are:
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget about the boolean functions available for use in the IIF function Now you can at a glance see the list of functions, their list of parameters and their official explanations
http://feeds.feedburner.com/IdentityLifecycleManagerilmBestPractices</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM &#34;2&#34; confirmHumanity=&#34;false&#34;</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-confirmhumanity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 12:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-confirmhumanity.html</guid>
      <description>With Joe&amp;rsquo;s permissions I am posting the comment he&amp;hellip; David Lundell - Dec 3, 2008
With Joe&amp;rsquo;s permissions I am posting the comment he attempted to post earlier:
Apologies for spoiling the fun, but the confirm humanity config setting has no effect in ILM “2”.
This config setting is leftover from the early days of the product when we included Captcha support for AuthN. Setting this to true meant that users would go through a Captcha gate during AuthN, much like I had to do when submitting a comment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM &#34;2&#34; confirmHumanity=&#34;false&#34;</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-confirmhumanity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 12:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-confirmhumanity.html</guid>
      <description>I was getting ready to try out some of the various installation topologies that may be possible with ILM &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; including: separating the Portal and the Service (definitely possible), having two portals point back to the same service (I think it&amp;rsquo;s possible), when I came across the most interesting item in the ILM &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; installation guide in the section on Installing the ILM Service and ILM Portal on separate servers. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if you can spot it too:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Problems VS Technical Problems</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 17:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</guid>
      <description>I like how you linked business problems to technic&amp;hellip; William Wagner - Sep 4, 2011
I like how you linked business problems to technical problems. I think they affect each other in a lot of ways. You always need to balance them so you can succeed.
form an llc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Problems VS Technical Problems</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 17:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/business-problems-vs-technical-problems.html</guid>
      <description>A business problem is when employees can&amp;rsquo;t execute their job duties in an efficient fashion. In fact sometimes they are unable to complete the tasks at all. Business problems are especially costly when they directly affect customers. These problems can cause cash flowing into the company to be delayed as a customer waits to place an order, or to receive goods (and hence to pay), they can cause revenue to be lost as a customer temporarily takes their business to a competitor or a finds a substitute, sometimes this leads to customers forming new business relationships and loss of all future revenue from that customer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILM 2 Web Services Part 1 and 1/2</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 03:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/ilm-2-web-services-part-1-and-12.html</guid>
      <description>A few days after my post about setting up the ILM 2 Web Service reference Joe Schulman and others from the ILM product group began a new blog designed to fill in the gaps in the knowledge in the community about how to use the web services. So far the blog looks great and is a welcome addition to my knowledge and the communities knowledge base! Great job Joe and Company and thanks for the link to my blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live@edu Partner Airlift and SQL PASS, Flat Tires, and Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/liveedu-partner-airlift-and-sql-pass.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 03:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://identitymanaged.netlify.app/2008/12/liveedu-partner-airlift-and-sql-pass.html</guid>
      <description>As for me why no posts since Nov 11th &amp;ndash; well, I have attended the Live@edu Partner Airlift in Redmond, SQL PASS, had a flat tire, and enjoyed Thanksgiving. In this post
I attended the Live@edu Partner Airlift in Redmond to see what&amp;rsquo;s new under the sun for schools and universities. Exchange Labs is now available on a widespread basis (see fellow MVP Almero Steyn&amp;rsquo;s blog posts on Live@edu and on Exchange Labs) !</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
